welcome back
and today we're going to see the MV tier
and the main issue right now is sourcing enough aluminum
as we have seen in the past episode
sourcing the raw aluminum is not easy
mainly because the every way of sourcing aluminum requires an MV electrolyzer
the other ways have a really low yield and are not really worth it
but we managed to get a little bit of aluminum in other ways
and we use that to make the aluminum required to make an MV electrolyzer
and that means that we can finally electrolyze all sorts of things to get a lot of aluminum
now that we have a better source of aluminum
we can move on to the next useful machine
which is going to be the extruder
this machine will make many craftings way easier and more straightforward
but most importantly
it will make many craftings have a way better yield than if we did those manually
using such machine requires us to put a shape with the material we want to be shaped inside the machine
that means we have a lot of shapes to manage
and to do that
we can put a item holder on the machine
and then we can access it and leave our molds there
and we can also use it to make higher tier tools
but be careful
because if you want for example to make a better hammer part like this one
it will take half an hour to do
so not only your machine will be clogged for half an hour
if you run out of power for one second after 20 minutes of progress
you will lose those 20 minutes of progress
and have to start over the process
my suggestion is to get another extruder
maybe with a battery too, if you want to do those parts and are not too confident
and with that we go to the point where we should probably figure out a better way of managing our power
because this turbine can only power one machine
and we have three on a single cable
now, most people like to have many generators
craft many many many turbines
put one turbine on each machine
and then have a pipe probably of benzene or diesel at this point of the game to power everything
but I don't like building so many turbines and having all of those around
so instead, I'm going to try to centralize power in a main battery buffer
many people probably don't like doing it this way
but I really like to centralize power earlier rather than later
so we have to use better buffers
right now we can basically only do MV
and the first thing we have to do is decide which battery buffer
and of course we do go with the biggest one
the only difference is the amount of cable you have to put in there
but I think it totally worth to always put the thicker cable to get extra slots
the main difference is the amount of batteries you can put inside it
so this one can only hold one battery and it cheap
while this one can hold 16 but it's a bit expensive
but once again
you can use this one with a single battery
costs a little bit more
the other big difference is the capacity
if you look this one with a single battery has only a thousand capacity
while the big one has one hundred thousands
and that capacity is the internal capacity of the block itself
which basically means extra free power storage
on the biggest one, it's almost half a battery
and of course the other thing we're going to need is batteries
now, lithium batteries at MV are the best batteries we could make
but I will keep lithium for later
I don't have much
it's a little bit hard to obtain
instead, I got a lot of sodium from processing sodalite and lazurite
so may as well put this sodium into the batteries
and that should make a really cheap setup to make
finally, for this setup we have to pick a cable
now at this point of the game, we have many options
so you most likely are going to look into annealed copper
which looks like the best one probably you can do right now
if you want to cheap out, you can use normal copper
which however has twice the power loss
what I was looking at
iron looks
nickel looks decent too
but I really don't see it being worth the extra loss
but the bigger thing here is that you shouldn't watch just the cables of your tier
because at this point for example
we can totally use gold or silv—
or maybe not gold
but we can totally use silver
we getting silver right now is easy
it's a super easy metal to process
you don't have to blast furnace it
and as you can see
it's only one cable loss
but it's only one amp
and this one can do even 500 volts
so this cable...
like the voltage is the maximum—
okay, that should not confuse you with machine parts
okay, if you look at the machine cable, diodes or machine hulls
they say also voltage out
but we're going to talk about those later
the thing is that its maximum voltage
that means you can use a silver cable in every tier up to HV
we are at MV, 128 (volts)
so we can use HV cables too
and silver is an option
even better than silver, I would suggest blue alloy
and I think blue alloy is so good
that it's what I'm going to do
blue alloy is basically silver plus electrotine
so at the end of the day
the cost is the same per wire
it's always one silver ingot makes either one silver cable or one blue alloy cable
but blue alloy can carry twice the amount of current
that means you can use a cable that is half the size
or you can carry twice the power with the same cable
I think it's probably worth it to go dig electrotine
at this point I could just dig more silver
but electrotine, one ore gives you 10 dust
so it's quite nice
also it has a nice byproduct if you ever wanted to process it
and since it's a nether ore you also get twice as much
because nether ores have twice the yield
also at this point of the game
if you have to find a new vein you haven't found yet at this point of the game
you can also use the prospectors
you can actually craft this one at LV
it doesn't need much
it's a little bit annoying maybe to make
but you can totally do it, it's not that hard
the LV and MV versions are disappointing
especially with the materials you have available
well, they are really good enough I would say
but you have to be a little bit smart on how to use those
for example this LV version has a 3 by 3 chunk scan range
every vein is 3 by 3 chunks
that means if you scan in the middle of a vein
it will scan those nine chunks
and reveal one vein below you
but if you do that in a corner
so that it will scan the chunks of four different veins
it should reveal four veins
yes it did
and that, you can see how I spotted three veins with one click
so be a little bit careful on the size
basically, if it is 3 by 3, click in a corner
5 by 5, go in the middle of a vein
and it was then that I realized that to make batteries we need polyethylene
so we are going to momentarily pause the centralization of the power project
and we are instead going to work on polyethylene
now you can make polyethylene in different ways
but my favorite one which is probably the easiest one is to just use oil
and the easiest way to obtain oil is to look for one of those black spots in the map
it's rather common you can easily spot it in a desert
but you can find those pretty much everywhere if you look around enough
anyways, once you get there
you have to set up a pump
I mean you could use bucket
you can also get oil in many other ways
but I feel like at this tier it's the easiest way in my opinion
so I'm going to do it this way
so you set up a pump
you're going to need to power this one
since we have oil there
and a semIfluid generator uses almost no power
I suggest using that one
and then the pump should start working
okay, once you got the—
oh you have to give it mining pipes
once you start getting oil
you want to move it over to your base
so you can either make a normal pipe
or long distance fluid pipeline are really really nice if you want to use those
but since I'm only going to do a little bit of polyethylene
I think I'm simply going to fill up a tank
and then manually move the oil using cells from that tank to a tank I will have in my base
and once we have the oil
we can start processing it
now, the first step is going to be distilling it
since we don't have access to the distillation tower
we have to use this single distillery
which will make us pick one of the possible outputs
now, instead of looking at the different pages in NEI
you can just look at the distillation tower recipe
and then you see your outputs
basically those outputs you can pick there are those here
and simply use the circuit to pick which one you want
so one would be heavy, two light, three naphtha and four gas
there is also lubricant I think
yeah, and there is also lubricant that is not in the distillation tower
I say that because you can easily figure out which ratios you get
it's easier to compare the outputs if you look at this page rather than looking that
and we are going with the sulfuric light fuel
because we get just so much more
naphtha will make more ethylene in the later step
but we got more than twice as much light fuel
and it ends up being more convenient
I think, I'm not even too sure
probably naphtha is a little bit more energy efficient actually, now that I think about it
but still I'm going to go with light fuel
so if I need it, I can also burn it in a combustion generator
so with that said, we start by putting the oil into a tank
then we're going to use a pump into a distillery
in the future
depending what you want to do
you can do it in totally different ways
I'm just improvising
if you want to use oil as fuel
you probably want to set up it with a pipe
so you can have multiple distilleries
because a single distillery is rather slow
but since I only want a little bit of polyethylene
that's going to be enough
so I'm going to use circuit
is that a two or a three? two
and we have to power this one
now my idea was to power this with the upcoming centralized power
but right now I can't make batteries
because first I have to finish that
so for the moment, I'm going to power this with a battery
and I'm charging this battery in the LV machines on top
I only need a little bit of polythene to get the first battery
then we can power it properly
so that's gonna give us sulfuric light fuel
next up is a chemical reactor
which goes over there
the fluid that goes into the chemical reactor
now we have it
and now here we have to figure out all of those sets
so for the moment, I'm just going to input this
this one can be electrolyzed to get back the hydrogen
or you can use it to make sulfuric acid
I think I'm most likely going to electrolyze it
it's a little bit easier to do
so to manage the recipe, I'm going to move automatically the fluid
from this input to the next machine
which is supposed to be another chemical reactor
there
we set the auto fluid output
and give it this cell
okay, that should already work
I think it needs more cells
how many
oh, 12 buckets
okay it's halfway through
okay, eventually this one will process the fluid
and send it to the next stage
but thing is that we have to feed in more hydrogen cells, ideally automatically
and recover the two outputs
so to manage those two cells and get back this hydrogen
all we have to do is to basically put those two in an MV electrolyzer to get back this one
but we have to worry about this sulfur too
so to do that, we simply put an electrolyzer like this
and a conveyor belt
this will move the cells over there
every five seconds it moves one
it also had those two from the test earlier
we are also going to power those later
so I'm leaving the space behind for the cables later
for the moment, I will power LV machines with batteries
and as soon as I get polyethylene I can add the MV battery to connect the MV machine
anyways recycling this one right now is nothing either
but let's finish this setup too
so this one only produces solids
I'm going to output the solids on the top
this one goes there
now we have to split the sulfur from the cell
so we got the sulfur there
we can simply leave a sulfur dust in there
it will lock the space
if you have a pipe like this
the pipe has a routing value, as you can see
that basically decides where items go
all you need to know is that shorter distance is the first thing that gets the items
so it will always go to the shorter path
that means this one outputs to this one
this one finds an output there
so it goes there
while this one is a longer route
it will be the lowest priority
so it will put items in there
sulfur goes right there
cell goes there
cannot go into the sulfur tank(drawer)
it will go back into this one
and we got the hydrogen there
now if you remove it though, this one frees up
and it could get the cell and get stuck
so you can make this key to lock the drawer
that way, even if you empty it, it still locks the filtering
you can make that thing to filter items if you want in the early game
but ideally as soon as you get polyethylene
you can make filters and make a filter cover which is likely better
but super early game you can filter items this way
anyways, when this one we get MV power
it will be able to recover those two cells and get back the hydrogen
here we got the light fuel
which is that
the next step is to add some
steam
and we need the steam inside our cell now
so we're going to have here cell looping tool
and we also need steam
so I'm going to have cells go back and forth between those two
to do that we can put two conveyors there
but you need to allow the input, otherwise
like if you have two covers
one pushing onto the other
they will not allow the items to move
unless you allow the items to go through
okay so if I put some cells in there
it should be able to move back and forth
now give me a moment to pipe in steam
OK, so I got the steam piped into the tank
we put some cells
and every five seconds those should move over there
perfect
we add the circuit and we need power too
okay
it should
okay it's working
this one then we output this lightly cracked fuel into a distillery with circuit 10
so there, circuit 10
and this one will output the cracked...
this one already makes ethylene, which is almost the last step
and I think this one needs some oxygen
but I'm going to do it manually
this one will produce a little bit of tiny dusts
want to just leave those there
there are ways of compressing those into normal dust
for the amount I'm going to get
I'm just going to forget about it inside of the drawer
anyways okay here we got this fluid did I forget something
oh yeah fluid auto-output
okay now I need, I'm manually
that's such an awful way of running machines
I'm manually giving those power with the LV batteries
but I only need a little bit of polyethylene to get a good battery
and then I'm going to centralize power with that battery
that's probably not how you should be playing but
I'm also showing you other ways of playing
which no one actually fully does like
nothing many other people play like that
but I like doing that kind of messed up things every now and then
and finally after all of that setup once we got some ethylene
we use circuit one with some oxygen
which I'm going to feed in the same way I do with the steam later
once I have a central oxygen system
we get polyethylene
and you can also use a redstone instead of batteries
but I think moving batteries is fun I guess
and there we have the polyethylene
which we can use to finally make batteries
MV batteries
and as I said a long time ago
I'm actually going to use sodium
because I want to keep lithium for the next tier
there we go
and with that, we are finally ready to centralize our power in MV
so we put our battery buffer wherever it can fit
try to figure out a place where all of your power can pass through
and I figured out I'm going to mainly use steam
so here is where all of my power is going
I only have five batteries now
later I will fill it up
every battery will allow you to extract one amp and insert two, by the way
and then I'm going to use a steam turbine
uh this one is empty
well, sooner I'm going to rely on this one
and this tank would be ...
I'm going to keep the steam tank for the steam multiblocks
I will disconnect the EBF from the steam there
and connect it to there, but slowly
the other turbine will go there
I started a new line
and those blocks can blow up if rain hits those on any side
so make sure the blocks are safe from rain
anyways this cable
this one outputs a single amp so I could use a ...
this cable can carry 4 turbines
later I'm going to add more turbines on this row
still planning it
time to calculate
it's like 20 solar per turbine if I remember correctly
yeah when I connected this one
I removed the steam from the already empty tank
and now we have crash
but whatever
so we put the power in there
also, figuring out the size of the cable can be a little bit tricky
I'm not sure even how to suggest you
like, ideally you should probably try to figure out what's the maximum current that is going through a cable
and use a cable that is thick enough
for example, this one with five batteries can only output five amps
so a cable capable of doing five amps is enough
but let's say I'm going to have 16 batteries
16 batteries is maximum 16 amps
so a 16 amp cable is going to be good enough
usually you pay attention at the output
but you can also try to work in reverse
and try to figure out what's the maximum (volt?) you have on a cable
but ideally it's better to just figure out how many amps you're going to push on a cable
this one with 16 batteries is 16 amps, so 16 amps cable
I'm charging up my batteries
now, I could go around with this cable
and just connect everything
that cable is max voltage HV
but I'm feeding it with an MV battery
so it's actually going to have MV power
but instead of doing that
I could totally do that
but to make it more future proof
and also to reduce the power loss
because this cable loses one EU per block regardless of how much you push
so 1/128 is way more of a loss than 1/500
basically, it will lose half of its power after 64 blocks, with that power
if we use HV power, it's going to lose half of the power after 200 blocks
so we're going to use HV power
and to get HV power we are going to use a transformer
and we have to remember that this cable
if we use a transformer
this one
when you put it, it's going to be in step down mode
so it doesn't really work like that
you have to hit it with the soft mallet
OK, soft mallet will reverse the working function of the transformer
and now you can see step up, output HV, four amps
so here I could use this cable
we have four amps HV
also by stepping up, you can use a four time smaller cable
because it's no longer 16 amps MV, but it's four amps HV
so I could use this cable
but once again, I'm going to future proof it and use thick cable
so this one will be good for when I will have a HV battery buffer with 16 batteries
or I could make four MV battery (buffers)
okay so on this cable now we have ideally up to four amps
right now it's probably going to be only one and a quarter of them
but it will have up to four amps
and now we can connect this cable to the actual base
I really prepare a little bit of lining
OK, the first thing I have to connect is the oil setup I did earlier
because otherwise I have not polyethylene
and let's have this cable go like that
okay, I have to be careful because once again this cable has HV power
my machines are LV
okay I think I'm going to do it like that
we go through or maybe just like this
so probably don't need such a thick cable anymore
use smaller cable
this one is MV
have to be careful
this is HV
this one there still has HV
so after that then MV transformer
this one will turn the HV back into MV
like this
now here we have MV but this machine is LV
so we have to be careful
you can put covers or paint cables to avoid making a mess
but always be careful
make a backup
this one was MV
I connected it and now we got the hydrogen
think I forgot the auto-output
did I set it up properly
oh wait solid auto output okay
can you push
okay sulfur goes in there
hydrogen in five seconds should go there
come on
should be five seconds I think
okay the hydrogen that work
now we have to power the LV machines
now this is one two three four five machines
so we could need up to five amps
but those are never going to work altogether full time I think
and I'm not really going to push this setup much
so 4 amps will do
and 4 amps is what a transformer outputs
now this one takes MV power and makes LV
and we keep using the same cable
because I don't like having multiple cables
most likely like
I think many people use different cable for every tier
that could help you figure out which tier a cable is
but I like more to use the same cable everywhere
so I have less different cables to worry about
that's probably not a good tip
but I also don't wanted to tell you to make an MV cable just so you don't confuse MV or HV or LV power
like I'm not going to use anneal copper
anneal copper or copper cables are horrible
like there isn't a good MV cable in my opinion
like iron and nickel have too much power loss
cupronickel too much power loss
copper and annealed copper have a single amp
and electrical steel is not easy to make
I don't think there is any good MV cable
so I'm just sticking with blue alloy which is HV however
so always try to figure out how to keep track of which tier is each cable
there are ways of painting cables
but at this tier
at this tier just try not to get confused
you shouldn't have too many cables to worry about
I mean that's only one more reason why people like to spam generators and have a few line instead of a main cable
but I like to play like that instead
I feel like it's way cleaner to have transformers right away and really centralized power
rather than having spamming turbines everywhere on different tiers
we can also see the power going in
okay and it's not really getting much power right now
because it's trying to fill up
okay, once this one is filled up
the pressure will go to this pipe to the turbine and charge it up
so next I'm going to try to hook up the EBF
I haven't managed to make the ...
it's called the other thing yet
give me a moment trying to figure out how it's called
d d d d d
and I don't have MV hatches yet
so I'm going to stick to those
we put a transformer in there
once again, here we have to be even more careful with the voltage stuff
because we have to minimize the power loss of the cables
like we had before with generators
but thing is that the transformer got changed
so it's no longer an issue
transformers used to be able to only accept one amp
so if you had too much cable loss on the cable that will get to the transformer
that will sum up
and it will be hard to get enough power
but transformers now can accept two amps
that makes up for the power loss
and once again, I have to be careful because here I need MV
but this cable here is HV
maybe working like that is not really the best for new players
maybe you should stick
upvolting that early may be a little bit tricky to manage if you don't know well enough how the electricity mechanics works
I like to play like that
I'm experienced
maybe shouldn't be suggesting this to new people
I don't even know what my target is anymore
here we have MV goes into the LV transformer
with a really ugly cabling
and this one should be able to run
good
and that's going to drain a lot of power now
yep power outputs way more than the input
still have to finish this line of solar boilers
I'm probably going to make a lot of solar boilers
like so
that's going to be good for the beginning of MV at least
and then to avoid confusion
I'm also going to paint the cables
now I'm doing this mostly for you guys
but I wouldn't do that if I wasn't doing a video
so early game you can use those paint brushes
there is also this one which should work
I think this one uses paint by the way
ideally you want to get this spray cans maybe
but those are super easy to craft
anyway that was saying I'm going to paint the cables like so
so we know yellow is HV
if you shift click, it will paint the whole row
like that, there
come on
oh, it also painted transformer okay
the transformer is not supposed to be painted
and MV will be orange
now this is yellow
and MV is orange
by the way the color I'm using is the color of the name of the tiers
like that's one standard
I think the color most people use is the tier name
like if you look at the thing there
if you look voltage in
there is the value and then there is the tier
every tier has kind of a color
trying to follow the color of the name of the tier with cables when I paint cable apart
(if) I wasn't making a video
I wouldn't even paint the cable apart
that can be really helpful for people not to get confused
I heavily suggest painting cables if you do a multiplayer run
I would I only paint cables if I'm doing a multiplayer run or if I'm making a video
otherwise I wouldn't even paint
but it can be really helpful not to get confused and to avoid accidental clicks
okay so the good spray can to paint cables should be this one
it's a little bit more convoluted to craft
because you have to process the paint into chemical paint
and then you have to fill up the can with a canning machine
it's a little bit more upset
but it has 500 usage which is way better
and if you misclick and wrongly click color something
either you make a solvent can which has 1000 usages
but it takes acetone
we are going to need a lot of acetone
but right now it's a little bit annoying to make
the other solution, if it is a single misclick, you can use a water bucket
so you take a bucket of water
and you pour it over the mispainted block to unpaint it
also the good (?) thing about paints is
if you paint the two cables like that
as you can see, the different painted cables cannot be connected
so that's super helpful to avoid mistakes
and by having a better buffer it's also way easier to power an arc furnace
which we can also use in our next passive processing line
this line will produce out of nowhere oxygen and silicon, solar grade silicon
so we start with a rock breaker that make cobblestone
forge hammer into gravel
forge hammer into sand
arc furnace into glass
forge hammer into glass dust
centrifuge into silicon dioxide
from which we extract Silicon
and we also get a lot of oxygen
that's going to be the main source of oxygen for our base for a long time
and then we further refine the raw silicon into silicon solar grade
by using this two step setup
I think you can easily figure out the recipes in NEI
I think I have shown all of it anyways
and now that we have solar grade silicon
we can finally make the silicon boules
which will take a lot of time to be produced inside our EBF
and with those, we now have access to higher tier of technology
like the MV energy hatches
which will allow us to build a more powerful EBF
capable of running at 500 EU per tick
now we have to do maintenance
and this time we're going to do the maintenance with the field engineer's toolbox
so we have to fill in all of the tools and the solder
and there we go
fixed
and with that new EBF
we can finally start producing stainless steel
the material required for HV machines
even though we don't have the circuit yet
but just with this one is all we need to make
and that means we can make an HV battery buffer
to put this one in place we are simply going to reroute the cables
so the yellow line is already up there
there it goes
put in the batteries
and we can disconnect the old thing
I already turned off the EBFs
otherwise they will power fail
a little bit of rewiring
this cable up there was MV
but it's fine to feed MV into HV
the only issue is that if you feed like four amps of MV into an HV
you are using four amps of the capacity
this one for example can take eight amps
but it's either eight amps of MV or HV
so maybe I will probably put a transformer there
to turn those four amps into one
but I'm going to build more solar boilers too
and finally I'm also going to
okay, it's draining all of the capacity of this one into that one, good
okay and now
I can just leave this one process, the Kanthal, which we will need for the next upgrade
that's going to take some time
also this ingot, as you can see, is not a normal ingot it's a hot ingot
so it has to be cooled down
and to cool down those hot ingots
for the moment all we can do is use a chemical bath with some coolant
this process will produce some hot coolant as leftover
now since we want to recover this one to make fresh coolant to keep the process going
we can use a vent like this on a bucket of water
and that should, after a little bit, move the hot coolant back into normal coolant
okay and after a while it moves back
as always, at this stage of the game, try to really look into every quest you can find in the quest book
like the quest book should explain all of those things really nicely
so I'm mostly showing a little bit the main steps
but my biggest suggestion for the first tiers up to HV is going to be just read the quest book
anyways, we use kanthal to upgrade our EBF so that it can smelt silicon
once again, that silicon has to be cooled down in the chemical bath
and now that we finally have access to silicon
we can make transistors
which we unlock the advanced circuit
and with those, we have everything of what was required to unlock the next tier, HV
but before we actually can afford powering HV machines
we have to increase our power generation
since as you can see, we can barely keep up at the moment
and also our solar boiler are starting to calcify
those boilers indeed every one or two days more or less they start losing the output
as you can see
those don't have a full output
the older one have some lower outputs
that's because they calcified
so every one or two days I don't remember
I think it's 12 hours of the game running
you have to break those and put those down again
so that the calcification goes away
so probably we're going to have to look into a better power source
and of course when I say probably, we all know deep down what that actually means
and I think that's enough for today
see you next time for a high voltage tier
欢迎回来
今天我们来看看 MV 等级的事情
目前的主要问题是搞到足够的铝
上集我们已经看到了
获取生铝是个麻烦事
主要是因为搞铝的大部分方法基本都需要一台 MV 电解机
其他方法产量太低 不值得
但是我们设法通过其他方式得到了一点铝
随后用这些铝制作了 MV 电解机
这意味着我们终于可以电解各种东西得到大量的铝了
现在我们有了更稳定的铝来源
我们可以继续搞下一台有用的机器
压模机
这台机器将使许多合成变得更加方便 步骤更少
但最重要的是
它还使许多合成比我们手工制作的产量更高
使用这种机器需要把模具和我们想加工的材料一起放进机器里
意味着我们有很多模具要收纳管理
为了让收纳管理轻松一点
我们可以在机器上放一个槽位扩展覆盖板
然后在这里打开它 把模具放里面
我们也可以用它来制造更高级的工具
但要注意
如果你想做一个好一点的部件 比如这个锤头
它的加工时长将近半个小时
所以不仅你的机器得堵半个小时
而且在加工了 20 分钟后哪怕只是跳电一秒钟
这 20 分钟的进度就全没了
只能从头再来
我的建议是再搞一台压模机
如果你想搞那些零件又不太放心 也许可以再加个电池
同时 到了这一步 我们或许该找个更好的管理电力的方法了
因为这台蒸汽轮机只能驱动一台机器
而我们在这一根线缆上接了三台机器
大多数人喜欢多堆一些发电机
于是就做很多很多很多气轮机
然后给每台机器都装一个气轮机
最后接一根苯或柴油的管道来给所有东西供电
但我不喜欢造一堆气轮机到处放
因此 我打算把电力集中存储在电池箱中
很多人可能不喜欢这样做
但我更喜欢尽早中心化供电 而不是拖到后面
所以我们要弄点电池箱
现在我们基本上只能做 MV 的
而我们要做的第一件事是决定做多大容量的电池箱
当然我们要做最大的那个
不同容量的电池箱合成配方 唯一的区别是使用的导线粗细
但我认为用更粗的导线 做大容量的版本是完全值得的
而用起来的主要区别 是可放入其中的电池数量
就比如这个只能装一个电池 且比较便宜
而这个可以装 16 个 但有点贵
但别忘了
你可以只给这个塞一颗电池
成本只高一点
另一个很大的区别是缓存容量
你看这个单节电池只有八千缓存
而大的有十万
这个就是它本身的内部容量
基本上意味着额外的免费电力存储空间
在最大的这一个上 它几乎是半个电池
当然 我们需要的另一样东西是电池
现在 MV 的锂电池是我们能制造的最好的电池
但我打算把锂留到之后再用
我没有多少
它也点难获得
相反 我从方钠石和青金石处理中得到了大量的钠
所以不妨把这些钠放进电池里
这应该是个非常便宜的方案
最后 我们需要针对这个方案选择一根线缆
此时此刻我们有很多选择
所以 你很有可能会考虑退火铜
它看起来是你现在能做的中最好的一个
如果你想省一点 你可以使用普通铜
然而 它的线损是（退火铜的）两倍
而我在看……
铁-（注：这条字幕直接删了吧 完全没法翻译）
镍看起来也还行
但我真的不认为值得为它承受更高的线损
但更重要的是 你不应该只看当前等级的线缆
因为比如在这个时候
我们完全可以用金或者银-
或者不包括金
但是我们完全可以用银的
我们现在获得银很容易
这是一种超级容易加工的金属
你不需要用高炉处理它
同时如你所见
它线损只有 1
不过也只能传 1 安
以及 这个甚至可以传 500 伏电压
所以这条线缆…
大概 电压最大值-
好吧 这不应该让你把机器外壳混淆
好吧 如果你看看机器线缆、二极管或机器外壳
他们说也有电压输出
但我们以后再谈这些
重点是它的最大电压
这意味你每个等级都可以用银线缆 一直用到 HV
我们现在在 MV 128（伏）
所以我们也可以使用 HV 线缆
而银是可选项之一
而比银更好的话 我建议使用蓝色合金
我认为蓝色合金很不错
这就是我要做的
蓝色合金基本上是银加蓝石
而在最后
每根电线的成本相同
总是一个银锭做一根银线缆或一根蓝色合金线缆
但是蓝色合金可以承载两倍的电流
这意味着你可以使用一半粗细的线缆
或者你可以用同样的线缆携带两倍的能量
我想去挖蓝石矿可能是值得的
在这一点上 我可以挖更多的银
但是蓝石矿 一个矿石给你 10 个粉
所以挺不错的
如果你想处理它的话它也有很好的副产
同时因为它是下界矿石 你也能得到两倍的量
因为下界矿石的产量会翻倍
以及在这个时候
如果你必须找到一条你还没见过的新矿脉
你也可以用探矿仪
你实际上可以在 LV 制作这东西
它不需要太多（材料）
制作起来可能有点麻烦
但你完全可以做到 这没那么难
LV 和 MV 版本有些力不从心
尤其是用你现在可用的材料
嗯 我想说的是他们足够好
但得稍微动点脑筋来用
比如这个 LV 版扫描范围是 3x3 区块
每条矿脉都是 3 乘 3 区块
这意味着如果你在矿脉正中间扫描
它会扫描这九个区块
同时只扫描出你下面的这一条矿脉
但是如果你在角上扫
这样它就会扫描四个属于不同矿脉的区块
它应该会扫描出四条矿脉
是的 确实如此
你可以看到我是如何一键发现三条矿脉的
所以要注意一下扫描范围
基本上 如果是 3x3 那就在角上扫
5x5 在矿脉正中间扫
然后我意识到要聚乙烯来做电池
所以我们要暂时搁置中心化供电计划
转而研究聚乙烯
现在你可以用不同的方法制造聚乙烯
我喜欢的一个也是最简单的一个 就是直接用石油
而获取石油最简单的方法就是在地图上找一个这样的黑点
在沙漠里很容易就能发现
如果你多转转的话 几乎哪里都能找到
不管怎样 一旦你到了那里
你必须设好一个泵
我是说 你可以用桶
你也可以通过许多其他方式获得石油
不过我的观点是这一阶段这样做最简单
所以我要这样做
所以你设置了一个泵
你需要给这个供电
既然那里有石油
同时半流体发电机几乎不需要电力
我建议用那个
然后泵应该开始工作了
OK 一旦你得到了-
哦 你还得给它采矿管道
在你开始得到石油后
你想把它转移到你的基地
所以你要么做一个普通的管道
或者长距离流体管道也很好用 如果你想用那个的话
但因为我只需要一点点聚乙烯
我想我只装满一储罐
然后使用流体单元手动将石油从储罐移动到我基地中的石油储罐中
一旦我们有了石油
我们可以开始处理它
第一步是蒸馏它
因为我们现在做不了蒸馏塔
我们只能使用这个蒸馏室
这将使我们只能选择所有可能输出中的一种
现在 与其在 NEI 中挨个翻页看
你完全可以直接看蒸馏塔的配方
然后你会看到你要的输出
基本上你可以选择的输出就是这里的那些
简单地调整编程电路来选择你想要哪一个
所以一号是重油 二号是轻油 三号是石脑油 四号是炼油气
我想还有润滑油
对 而且还有不在蒸馏塔配方里的润滑油
我这么说是因为你可以很容易地看到你得到的比率
如果你查看这个页面而不是查看那个页面 更容易比较输出的异同
我们将选择的是含硫轻燃油
因为我们这样得到的产出多太多了
石脑油能在比较后期的步骤中制造更多的乙烯
但我们得到了的轻燃油是它的两倍多
所以还是它更方便
我这样想 我甚至有些不确定
也许石脑油能效好一点 实际上 现在我在思考这件事
但我还是要选择轻燃油
这样如果我需要的话我也可以在内燃发电机里烧
这样 我们首先将石油放入储罐
然后我们要用泵送进蒸馏室
在以后
取决于你想做什么
你可以用完全不同的方法
我只是临时凑合
如果你想用石油作为燃料
你可能会想弄套管道
这样你可以有多个蒸馏室
因为单个蒸馏室相当慢
但我一开始只想要一点点聚乙烯
那这样就足够了
所以我要修改编程电路
是二号还是三号来着？ 二号
随后我们需要给这东西供电
我的想法是把它接入即将建造的中心化供电方案
但现在我做不了电池
因为我需要先把这东西弄好
所以当下 我先用电池给它供电
以及我在用顶部的 LV 机器为电池充电
我只需要一点聚乙烯就能搓出第一块电池
然后我们就可以正式接电了
所以这会给我们提供含硫轻燃料
接下来是化学反应釜
就放在这里
流体自动输出到化学反应釜里
这样就配置好了
现在我们要研究下用哪套配方
对于当下 我就直接输入这个了
这个可以电解以取回氢气
或者你可以用它来制造硫酸
我想我很可能会电解它
这样做起来简单些
所以为了继续这个配方 我需要自动将流体
从这个输入到下一台机器
也就是另一个化学反应釜
放那里
设置自动流体输出
并给它这个流体单元
OK 现在应该已经开始工作了
我想它需要更多流体单元
多少来着
哦 12 桶
好吧已经凑够一半了
好吧最终这个会处理液体
并将其送入下一阶段处理
但问题是我们需要塞更多的氢流体单元 最好是自动的
并还原这两个产物
所以为了处理这两个单元并取回氢气
我们所要做的就是基本上把这两个放在 MV 电解机里 从而还原出这个
但我们同时还得处理掉这些硫
所以要做这个 我们只需要这样放一个电解机
和传送带
这会把流体单元移到那边
每五秒钟它就移一个
它也有之前测试中的那两个
我们过会在为这块供电
所以我在这里留了点以后用来走线的空间
目前 我将用电池为 LV 机器供电
而后只要我弄到聚乙烯 我就可以添加 MV 电池来接入 MV 机器
不管怎样 现在回收这个也没什么用
但让我们搓完这套方案再说吧
所以这个只产生固体
我要输出顶部的固体
这个接到这里
现在我们要把硫从流体单元中分离出来
所以我们在这里拿上硫
我们可以简单地把硫粉留在这里
它会锁定存储
如果你有这样的管道
如你所见 管道有一个路由值
这基本上决定了物品的去向
你只需要知道距离越短越优先收到物品
所以它总是会走较短的路径
这意味着这个会输出到这个
这个在那里找到一个输出
所以它去那里
而这条路线更长
这将是最低优先级
所以它会把东西放这里
硫放在这里
流体单元放在那里
不会进入硫的抽屉
它会回到这个里面
这样这里就有氢气了
如果你现在把它拿走 这个位置就空出来了
它可能会收到单元并卡住
不过你可以做个这样的钥匙把抽屉锁上
这样 即使你掏空它 它仍然会锁定过滤
如果你想在游戏早期过滤物品 你可以做这个东西
但理想情况下 只要你得到聚乙烯
你就可以制作过滤器 从而制作可能更好用的过滤器传送带覆盖板
但是游戏超级早期你可以这样过滤物品
不管怎样 当这个我们接入 MV 电力后
它将能够还原这两个单元并取回氢气
这样 我们得到了轻燃油
也就是这个
下一步是添加一些
蒸汽
我们需要单元里有蒸汽
所以我们需要做个循环利用单元的工具
我们还需要蒸汽
所以我需要让单元在这两者之间来回移动
为此 我们可以在这里放两个传送带
但你需要允许输入 否则
就好比你放了两个覆盖板
一个推到另一个
他们不会允许物品移动
除非你允许物品通过
OK 如果我在里面放一些流体单元
它应该可以来回移动
现在给我一点时间来接入蒸汽管道
OK 我把储罐接入蒸汽
我们放一些流体单元
这样每隔 5 秒钟 它们就会移到那边
完美
我们配置编程电路 我们还需要电力
OK
它应该（注：和上面一行合并吧）
OK 开始工作了
然后我们将这个轻裂化燃油输出到编程电路为 10 的蒸馏室
这里 10 号电路
这个会输出裂化的…
这已经能出乙烯了 差不多是最后一步了
我想这个需要一些氧气
但我打算手动提供
这个会产生一点小搓粉
我让它留在这里好了
有办法把它们压缩成普通粉
以我将得到的量来说
我打算直接把它塞抽屉里不管了
不管怎样 好吧 我们得到了这种液体 我忘记了什么吗？
哦 对 流体自动输出
好吧 现在我需要 我手动
这种给机器凑合供电的方式太糟糕了
我在用 LV 电池手动供电
但我只需要一点聚乙烯就能做出一个好电池
然后我要用那个电池来把电力中心化
这可能不是你应该走的游玩流程 但是
我这里也在向你们展示其他的玩法
没有人会真的完全喜欢的那种
没有多少人这样玩
但我喜欢时不时乱搞些类似的事
最后 在这套方案全都完成后 我们会得到一些乙烯
我们用一号编程电路 再加上一些氧气
我稍后会把它和蒸汽一样接过来
在我有了中央供氧系统的时候
我们现在得到了聚乙烯
你也可以用红石代替电池
但我觉得来回倒电池……有趣一点 大概
然后 我们得到了聚乙烯
终于可以用它来制造电池了
MV 电池
正如我很久以前所说的
我打算用钠
因为我想留着锂下个等级再用
就这样
有了这个 我们终于准备好将我们的电力在 MV 时期就中心化了
所以我们把电池箱子随便找个合适的地方放
最后试着找出一个所有的供能线路都会经过的地方
而我认为我将主要使用蒸汽
所以这就是我所有供能线路都会经过的地方
我现在只有五块电池
稍后我会填满它
每个电池可以输出 1 安 输入 2 安 顺便说下
然后我放个蒸汽轮机
呃 它已经空了
好吧 我很快就会换成依赖这个
这个蓄水器就直接…
我要把这个蒸汽蓄水器留给蒸汽多方块机器
我会在这里断开 EBF 的蒸汽
随后将蒸汽接到这里 不过得慢慢来
另一个蒸汽轮机就放这里
我弄了条新产线
以及这些方块如果任何一面碰上雨水都可能爆炸
所以需要确保这些方块不会淋雨
不管怎样 这条线缆
这个输出 1 安 这样我就可以用…
这条线缆可以承载 4 台蒸汽轮机
稍后我将在这一排增加更多蒸汽轮机
还在计划中
计算时间
每个蒸汽轮大概配 20 个太阳能锅炉 如果我没记错的话
好吧 当我接这个的时候
我相当于把已经空了的蓄水器里的蒸汽接走了
然后就跳电了
但不管怎样
所以我们把电源接到这里
此外 弄清楚合适的线缆尺寸可能有点棘手
我甚至不知道如何建议你
就像 理想情况下 你可能应该试着弄明白需要通过这条线缆的最大电流是多少
并使用足够粗的线缆
比如这个五块电池的只能输出五安电流
所以一根 5 安的线缆就足够了
但假设我有 16 节电池
16 节电池最大 16 安
所以一根 16 安的线缆就足够了
通常你只会注意输出侧
但你也可以尝试反着推
试着弄清楚线缆上的最大电压是多少
但理想情况下 只弄清楚你会在线缆上过多少安培就好了
这个带 16 块电池的是 16 安培 所以 16 安线缆
我在给我的电池充电
现在 我可以把这条线缆绕一圈
然后把所有东西都连上
这个线缆最大电压 HV
但我用 MV 电池给它供电
所以它实际上是 MV 电力
但与其这样做
我完全可以这么做
但为了让它更向前兼容
并减少电力损失
因为不管你传输多少 这条线缆每格都会损失 1 EU
所以 1/128 比 1/500 损失大得多
基本上 它会在 64 格后失去一半的电力 在这种电压下
如果我们使用 HV 电力 它会在 200 格后失去一半的电力
所以我们要用 HV 电力
为了获得 HV 电力 我们将使用变压器
同时我们还必须记住这条线缆
如果我们使用变压器
这个
当你放的时候 它会是降压模式
所以它不会像需要的那样工作
你必须用软锤敲一下
好的 软锤会切换变压器的工作模式
现在你可以看到升压 输出 HV  4 安
所以我可以用这条线缆
我们有四安 HV
此外 通过升压 线缆可以细到原来的 1/4
因为它传输的不再是 16 安 MV 而是 4 安 HV
这样我就可以用这条线缆了
但再一次 我要向前兼容 用粗线缆
这样在我开始用 16 块电池的 HV 电池箱的时候也它会很好用
或者我也可以做四个 MV 电池（箱）
好的 所以在这条线缆上 现在我们理想情况下有最高 4 安的电流
现在最多也就用个 1.25 安左右
但它最多有四安
现在我们就可以把这条线缆接到实际的基地了
我专门准备了些走线空间
好的 第一个需要接点的是我之前做的石油处理
不然的话我就没聚乙烯可用了
所以就让线缆这样走
好吧 我必须小心 因为这条线缆上的是 HV 电力
我的机器是 LV 的
好吧 我想我要这样做
我们把线穿过这里或者就像这样
所以可能不再需要这么粗的线缆了
使用更细的线缆
这个是 MV
必须小心
这是 HV
那根线上接的是 HV
所以在接下来 就是是 MV 变压器
这个会把 HV 变回 MV
像这样
现在我们有 MV 了但这台机器是 LV
所以我们还是需要小心
你可以放覆盖板 或者给线缆上色 以免搞混
但一定要小心
记得备份存档
这个是 MV
我把它接上电 这样我们得到了氢气
我想我忘了开自动输出
我设置得不对吗？
哦 等等 固体自动输出好的
你能输出吗
好的没问题 硫就去这里了
氢在五秒内就会去那里
来吧
我想应该是五秒钟
OK 氢气在正常走
现在我们得给 LV 机器供电了
现在这里有一二三四五台机器
所以我们最多需要 5 安
但我认为它们不会同时满功率运行
我也不打算把这套东西用的太过头
所以 4 安就可以了
正好 变压器输出的电流也是 4 安
现在这个取 MV 电输出 LV
以及我们一直使用相同的线缆
因为我不喜欢同时有多种线缆
大概就是
我觉得很多人会给每个等级用不同的线缆
这样能帮你分清线缆是哪个等级
但我更喜欢在任何地方使用相同的线缆
这样我不需要为各自不同种类的线缆费心
这可能不是个好建议
但我也不想直接告诉你做 MV 线缆 以免弄混 MV、HV 或 LV 电源
就像我不会用退火铜一样
退火铜或铜线缆很糟糕
在我看来 就像是 根本没有好用的 MV 线缆
就比如铁和镍的线损太大
白铜线损也太大
铜和退火铜只能传一安电
磁钢也不好做
我是觉得没有什么好的 MV 线缆
所以我就坚持使用蓝色合金 但它是 HV 的
因此一定要想办法记住每根线缆是哪个等级
有很多方法可以给线缆上色
但在这个等级
在这个等级尽量不要搞混
你应该不会为有太多不同种类的线缆发愁
这也是人们喜欢到处堆发电机、搞几条短线而不是做条主干线的又一个原因
但我喜欢这样玩
我觉得直接上变压器和中心化电力要干净得多
而不是各种地方都堆一堆不同等级的气轮机
我们能看到电力在往里输
好吧 它现在没获到多少电力
因为它试图填满
好吧 在这个装满了之后
压力会通过管道到达蒸汽轮机最后给它充电
所以接下来我要尝试连接 EBF
我还没有做出……
它还被称为另一个东西
给我一点时间想想它名字是怎么叫的
d d d d d
我现在还没有 MV 仓室
所以我得继续用这些
我们在这里放个变压器
再一次 这里我们必须更加小心电压的事情东西
因为我们必须最小化线缆的功率损耗
就像我们以前用发电机一样
但问题是变压器换了
所以这不再是问题了
变压器过去只能接受一安电力
所以如果你接到变压器的那根线的线损太高
损失会一点一点累积起来
最终导致很难获取足够的电力
但是变压器现在可以接受两安了
这弥补了线损
再一次 我必须小心 因为这里我需要的是 MV
但这里的线缆是 HV 的
也许这样干活对新玩家来说并不是很友好
也许你应该坚持
如果你对电力系统的机制了解不够 那么这么早升压可能带来一些麻烦
不过我喜欢这样玩
我经验丰富
也许不应该向新人建议这个
我都弄不清楚我的目标受众是谁了
这里接上 MV 进入 LV 变压器
配合着非常难看的走线
这东西应该就能正常运行了
好
这会消耗大量电力
是的 输出比输入多得多
还是得做完这排太阳能锅炉
我大概会做很多太阳能锅炉
像这样
这至少对 MV 前期有好处
然后为了避免混淆
我还要给线缆上色
现在我这么做主要是为了你们
如果我不拍视频我不是会这么做的
所以 游戏的早期你可以用这些刷子
还有这个应该也可以用
我记得这个会消耗染料来着
理想情况下 你可能最想弄到这个喷雾罐
但这些做起来非常容易
不管怎样 那是说我要像这样给线缆上色
所以我们知道黄色是 HV
如果你 Shift+点击 它会刷一整条
像这样 这样
给点力
哦 它还给变压器上了色 好的
变压器不应该上色
MV 是橙色
现在这些是黄色的
MV 是橙色的
顺便说一下 我用的颜色是等级名称的颜色
就像是 这算是个标准
我想大多数人用的颜色就是等级名
就比如你看这里写的
你看电压输入这块
它有个数值然后就是等级
每个等级都有对应的颜色
当我把线缆分开时 上色会时尽量按等级名称的颜色来
（如果）我不是在拍视频
我是不会给线缆上色区分的
但这对让人们不感到困惑真的很有帮助
尤其是玩多人模式的时候 我强烈建议给线缆上色
我只会在进行多人游戏或制作视频的时候给线缆上色
其他情况我就不上色了
但是它在避免混淆和避免意外点击真这块的很有帮助
好吧 所以那个比较好用的能给线缆上色喷雾罐应该是这个
制作起来有点复杂
因为你要把染料加工成化学染料
然后你必须用装罐机来装罐
些许令人沮丧
但它有五百点使用耐久 这可强太多了
如果你手滑 点错了颜色
那你要么做一个可以用一千次的的溶剂罐
它需要丙酮
尽管我们以后会需要大量的丙酮
但是现在就做的话会有点烦人
另一种解决方法是 如果只是手滑一次 你可以用水桶
所以你打一桶水
倒在涂错的方块上就能洗掉颜色
上色的好处是
如果你把两条线缆涂成这样
如你所见 不同颜色的线缆无法连接
所以这对避免错误发生非常有帮助
现在有了更好的电池箱 给电弧炉供电也容易多了
而电弧炉可以用在我们的下一条被动产线上
这条生产线能无中生有产出氧气和硅 太阳能级硅
所以我们从碎石机开始 它产出圆石
锻造锤打成沙砾
锻造锤打成沙子
电弧炉烧玻璃
锻造锤打成玻璃粉
离心成二氧化硅
我们从中提取硅
我们也同时获得了大量的氧气
在很长一段时间里 这将是我们基地的主要氧气来源
然后我们进一步将生硅精炼成太阳能级硅
通过这个两步处理流程
我想你可以很容易地在 NEI 里弄清用到的配方
我想我也已经完整展示了一遍就是
现在我们有了太阳能级硅
我们终于可以做单晶硅了
它会消耗大量时间在我们的 EBF 中生产
有了这些 我们现在可以接触更高等级的技术了
比如 MV 能源仓
这将使我们能够制作一个更强大的 EBF
能够以五百 EU/t 的功率运行
现在我们需要进行维护
这次我们将使用现场工程师工具箱进行维护
我们需要先放进去所有的工具和焊料
然后轻轻一点
修好了
现在有了新的 EBF
我们终于可以开始生产不锈钢了
也就是制作 HV 机器所需的材料
虽然我们还没做出来电路板
但我们只需要做这个
它意味着我们现在可以制作一个 HV 电池箱了
找个合适的地方放下 我们只需重新整理下线缆
所以 黄线已经在这里了
就这样
放进去电池
然后我们就可以直接断开旧线路了
我已经提前关闭了 EBF
不然的话他们会跳电
再来一点点重新理线
上面的线缆是 MV 的
但将 MV 输入到 HV 也没关系
唯一的问题是如果你把 4 安的 MV 电输入 HV
那你就在使用四安的容载了
例如 这个可以接受 8 安电力
但只能是 8 安 MV 或者 HV 中的一个
所以也许我可能会在这里放一个变压器
从而把四安转换成一安
但我也会建造更多的太阳能锅炉
最后我还要（注：1338-1339 间缺了两句没识别上）
好吧 它现在在把所有的电从这里吸到那里 挺好
好吧而现在
我可以在这里挂着坎塔尔合金了 它是下一次升级所需的材料
这会需要一些时间
以及正如你所看到的 这个锭不是普通的金属锭 而是一个热金属锭
因此它需要被冷却
而冷却的方法
目前我们所能用的只有加上了一些冷却液的化学浸洗机
这个过程会产生一些热冷却剂作为副产
既然我们想把这个回收来制造新的冷却液来让这个过程持续进行
我们可以像这样在这里装个散热器 对着一格水
这样应该每过一会就会将热冷却剂变回原来的冷却剂
好的 一段时间之后 冷却剂它自动回到了输入位置
像平常一样 在游戏的这个阶段 尽力去阅读你能在任务书中找到的每一个任务
任务书应该能很好地解释所有这些事情
而我主要展示的是一些主要步骤
但我对 HV 之前几个等级最大的建议就是好好看任务书
不管怎样 我们用坎塔尔合金来升级我们的 EBF 这样它就可以熔炼硅了
再一次 硅必须在化学浸洗机中冷却
现在我们终于有了硅
我们可以制造晶体管
从而解锁高级电路板的制作
有了这些 我们就有了解锁下一电压等级 HV 所需的一切
但是在我们真正供的起 HV 机器的电力之前
我们必须增加发电
正如你所见 我们现在就几乎跟不上了
我们的太阳能锅炉也在逐渐钙化
这些锅炉每隔一两天或多或少就会开始减少产出
如你所见
那些的输出是不满的
而更旧的输出就更低了
那是因为他们钙化了
所以每隔一两天还是多长时间 我不记得了
我想应该是游戏每运行 12 个小时
你就需要把这些拆掉重放一次
这样才能消除钙化
所以我们大概得找个更好的能源了
当然 当我说大概的时候 我们心里都知道实际指的是什么
我想今天的内容就这些了
下次 HV 等级见